{
  "category": "Microbiology",
  "difficulty": "easy",
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "What is the smallest living microorganism?",
      "options": [
        "Bacteria",
        "Virus",
        "Fungi",
        "Protozoa"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Virus",
      "id": "22FF327B-6442-4330-88BB-02D09131070D"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of cells lack a nucleus?",
      "options": [
        "Eukaryotic cells",
        "Prokaryotic cells",
        "Animal cells",
        "Plant cells"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Prokaryotic cells",
      "id": "FC9BEB28-57E7-4C1A-84D8-6B8DFB8094DD"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which microorganism is used in the making of bread and beer?",
      "options": [
        "Yeast",
        "Algae",
        "Protozoa",
        "Virus"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Yeast",
      "id": "E1009C07-C84C-4D66-B7C2-3D3410723B1E"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is not a type of bacteria?",
      "options": [
        "Spirilla",
        "Bacilli",
        "Cocci",
        "Fungi"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Fungi",
      "id": "D5015089-0D6F-461C-8417-E5ED307AB18E"
    },
    {
      "question": "What causes diseases like malaria and sleeping sickness?",
      "options": [
        "Protozoa",
        "Bacteria",
        "Virus",
        "Fungi"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Protozoa",
      "id": "7E7C9659-71EF-4420-9C3B-12E47FA16DF6"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of these is not a part of the bacterial cell structure?",
      "options": [
        "Cell Wall",
        "Mitochondria",
        "Plasmids",
        "Ribosomes"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Mitochondria",
      "id": "0201FA47-6CA0-4590-A7BF-1151DB136DF8"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the primary role of bacteria in the nitrogen cycle?",
      "options": [
        "They convert atmospheric nitrogen to a usable form for plants",
        "They convert nitrogen into atmospheric oxygen",
        "They help in the decomposition of plants and animals",
        "They prevent the over accumulation of nitrogen in the atmosphere"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "They convert atmospheric nitrogen to a usable form for plants",
      "id": "65042F22-5121-454F-89F9-C4F360EF394E"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the name of the process in bacteria that involves the transfer of genetic material from one bacterium to another?",
      "options": [
        "Fission",
        "Conjugation",
        "Transduction",
        "Translation"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Conjugation",
      "id": "A302A577-984C-4B28-AA67-33F886574D39"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which disease is caused by the bacterium 'Yersinia pestis'?",
      "options": [
        "Plague",
        "Typhoid",
        "Tuberculosis",
        "Cholera"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Plague",
      "id": "1C63BE34-B609-431E-9179-8F3E8038EE77"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of these is used to classify bacteria?",
      "options": [
        "Gram staining",
        "Ink staining",
        "Acid-fast staining",
        "All of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "All of the above",
      "id": "BEB0CD99-F9CA-4B9F-B97A-FE0EF1BCD36C"
    }
  ]
}
